catholiccourier.com 2019-05-19

# Privacy Policy | Catholic Courier

This privacy policy has been compiled to better serve those who are concerned with how their 'Personally Identifiable Information' (PII) is being used online. PII, as described in US privacy law and information security, is information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual in context. Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with our website.

**What personal information do we collect from the people that visit our blog, website or app?**

When ordering or registering on our site, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your name, email address, mailing address, phone number or other details to help you with your experience.

**When do we collect information?**

Users may be required to provide personally identifiable information in order to participate in or acquire specific types of services. For example, we may need to gather some personally identifiable information so that you can access such features as the online Diocesan Directory, or submit a Letter to the Editor, Calendar item or Reader Contribution; request or comment on news coverage; sign up for our e-Newsletters; purchase, cancel or change the address of a print subscription; request an advertising Media Kit; or purchase a Diocesan Directory or one of the other non-newspaper products we offer.

**How do we use your information?**

We may use the information we collect from you when you register, make a purchase, sign up for our newsletter, respond to a survey or marketing communication, surf the website, or use certain other site features in the following ways:

  * To quickly process your transactions.
  * To send periodic emails regarding your order or other products and services.
  * To follow up with after correspondence (live chat, email or phone inquiries)

**How do we protect your information?**

Our website is scanned on a regular basis for security holes and known vulnerabilities in order to make your visit to our site as safe as possible.

Your personal information is contained behind secured networks and is only accessible by a limited number of persons who have special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential. In addition, all sensitive/credit information you supply is encrypted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology.

To maintain the safety of all personal information, we implement a variety of security measures when a user places an order, enters, submits, or accesses their information.

All transactions are processed through a gateway provider and are not stored or processed on our servers.

**Links to Other Websites**

From time to time, we may make content from other websites available via links located on our website. Each website to which our website links will have its own individual privacy policy you should consult to determine how that website protects its visitors’ privacy. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of those other sites.

**Do we use 'cookies'?**

Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enable the systems of the site or service provider to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. For instance, we use cookies to help us remember and process the items in your shopping cart. They also are used to help us understand your preferences based on previous or current site activity, enabling us to provide you with improved services. We also use cookies to help us compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future.

**We use cookies to:**

  * Understand and save users’ preferences for future visits.
  * Keep track of advertisements.
  * Compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interactions in order to offer better site experiences and tools in the future. We also may use trusted third-party services that track this information on our behalf.

You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser settings. Since each browser is a little different, look at your browser's Help Menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies.

If you turn cookies off, it won't affect your user experience.

**Third-party disclosure**

We do not share, trade or otherwise transfer to outside parties personally identifiable information about you without your consent except, as necessary to provide you with services or information that you specifically request. For example, we may use your personally identifiable information to invite you to subscribe to e-newsletters from us. If you receive such an invitation and decline to subscribe, we will not send the newsletters to you.

We may compile information about you and other users of our website in a way that does not permit anyone reviewing the information to personally identify you (“aggregate information”). We may provide this non-personally identifiable, aggregate information to third parties for market analysis and other purposes.

In addition, we will share personally identifiable information with governmental authorities in response to subpoenas or other similar requests when legally required or authorized to do so, and will disclose information we collect about you under other circumstances as required by law.

**Third-party links**

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third-party products or services on our website. These third-party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

**Google**

Google's advertising requirements can be summed up by Google's Advertising Principles. They are put in place to provide a positive experience for users. <https://support.google.com/adwordspolicy/answer/1316548?hl=en>

We use Google AdSense Advertising on our website.

Google, as a third-party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our site. Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to our users based on previous visits to our site and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt-out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google Ad and Content Network privacy policy.

**We have implemented the following:**

  * **DoubleClick Platform Integration**  
We, along with third-party vendors such as Google use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookies) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) or other third-party identifiers together to compile data regarding user interactions with ad impressions and other ad service functions as they relate to our website.  
 
  * **Paypal Payment Processing**  
Paypal is the payment gateway and processor for all purchases made at CatholicCourier.com. Personally identifiable information, including credit card numbers, entered on our e-commerce forms are passed directly to Paypal and are not stored on our servers.

**Opting out:**  
Users can set preferences for how Google advertises to you using the Google Ad Settings page. Alternatively, you can opt out by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative Opt Out page or by using the Google Analytics Opt Out Browser add on.

**California Online Privacy Protection Act**

CalOPPA is the first state law in the nation to require commercial websites and online services to post a privacy policy. The law's reach stretches well beyond California to require any person or company in the United States (and conceivably the world) that operates websites collecting Personally Identifiable Information from California consumers to post a conspicuous privacy policy on its website stating exactly the information being collected and those individuals or companies with whom it is being shared. - See more at: <http://consumercal.org/california-online-privacy-protection-act-caloppa/#sthash.0FdRbT51.dpuf>

**According to CalOPPA, we agree to the following:**

Users can visit our site anonymously.

Once this privacy policy is created, we will add a link to it on our home page or as a minimum, on the first significant page after entering our website.  
Our Privacy Policy link includes the word 'Privacy' and can easily be found on the page specified above.

You will be notified of any Privacy Policy changes:

  * On our Privacy Policy Page

You can change your personal information:

  * By emailing us
  * By calling us
  * By logging in to your account

**How does our site handle Do Not Track signals?**  
We honor Do Not Track signals and Do Not Track, plant cookies, or display advertising when a Do Not Track (DNT) browser mechanism is in place.

**Does our site allow third-party behavioral tracking?**  
It's also important to note that we allow third-party behavioral tracking

**COPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act)**

When it comes to the collection of personal information from children under the age of 13 years old, the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) puts parents in control. The Federal Trade Commission and United States' Consumer Protection Agency enforce the COPPA Rule, which spells out what operators of websites and online services must do to protect children's privacy and safety online.

We do not market to children under the age of 13 years old.

**Fair Information Practices**

The Fair Information Practices Principles form the backbone of privacy law in the United States, and the concepts they include have played a significant role in the development of data protection laws around the globe. Understanding the Fair Information Practice Principles and how they should be implemented is critical to complying with the various privacy laws that protect personal information.

**In order to be in line with Fair Information Practices we will take the following responsive action, should a data breach occur:**  
We will notify the users via in-site notification

We also agree to the Individual Redress Principle, which requires that individuals have the right to legally pursue enforceable rights against data collectors and processors who fail to adhere to the law. This principle requires not only that individuals have enforceable rights against data users, but also that individuals have recourse to courts or government agencies to investigate and/or prosecute non-compliance by data processors.

**CAN SPAM Act**

The CAN-SPAM Act is a law that sets the rules for commercial email, establishes requirements for commercial messages, gives recipients the right to have emails stopped from being sent to them, and spells out tough penalties for violations.

**We collect your email address in order to:**

  * Send information, respond to inquiries, and/or other requests or questions
  * Process orders and to send information and updates pertaining to orders.
  * Send you additional information related to your product and/or service
  * Market to our mailing list or continue to send emails to our clients after the original transaction has occurred.

**To be in accordance with CANSPAM, we agree to:**

  * Not use false or misleading subjects or email addresses.
  * Identify the message as an advertisement in some reasonable way.
  * Include the physical address of our business or site headquarters.
  * Monitor compliance by third-party email marketing services, if used.
  * Honor opt-out/unsubscribe requests quickly.
  * Allow users to unsubscribe by using a link at the bottom of each email.

**If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, you can:**

  * Follow the instructions at the bottom of each email, and we will promptly remove you from our automated electronic correspondence.

**Contacting Us**

The General Manager of the Rochester Catholic Press Association, Inc., parent company of the Catholic Courier, is designated as the Data Protection Officer with respect to compliance with privacy laws. The General Manager can be reached using the information below. While users may choose to lodge a complaint with proper regulatory authorities, Catholic Courier is committed to addressing all complaints concerning users’ privacy, and will respond to all inquiries as soon as possible.

1150 Buffalo Rd  
Rochester, NY 14624 US  
585-529-9530 or 800-600-3628

Last revised on 2018-05-29
